In this section, we'll take a look at the HTP server implementation, which is a key component to the
wireless local area network application.
And of course, it supports the web page.
So let's get into the implementation overview, first of all, the Web server supports the web page
files, which includes the HTML document, the CSIS file and the JavaScript file, and will use this
web page to interact with the SB 32.
And that includes support for OTA or over the firmware updates and also displaying temperature and humidity
sensor readings.
And the web server will also be able to respond to connection and disconnection buttons, for example,
by entering the SSA, ID and password into text fields for the access point or router where you want
to connect and by clicking Connect, the connection attempts will be made.
And in the case that the ESP 32 is already connected to an access point, clicking disconnect will trigger
an action on the web server side that forces the SB 32 to disconnect.
Also, the webserver will be able to handle sending connection information to the Web page, such as
the suicide of the access point that the SB 32 is connected to and the IP and Gateway and Netmask signed
to the ESB.
And later in the course will display the side of the SB 32 itself on the web page.
So once you learn how to do all of these tasks, you'll know how to send data to the web page and receive
data from the page as well, which enables you to write your own custom LAN applications.
Now, let's talk about the Web page files, the resource files in this section includes an HTML file
that already includes the markup for the OTA update.
Basically, it is just a couple of buttons at this point, however, will expand upon this file throughout
the course, and the app does see a says file is the style sheet for the index edge HTML document,
and that will also continue to expand as we go along in the course.
And it already has the styling for the template that I've provided.
And also the Duchess file is the JavaScript file, which already includes the OTA functions and will
also expand this by adding functions throughout the course.
And the favicon that I could file is the icon that gets displayed in the address bar of the browser.
And lastly, the J Query file is the JavaScript library that enables the JavaScript functionality that
will be using.
Now, let's briefly talk about the 8TB server components of the IDF.
So here's the suggested reading for this section.
Be sure to check out the HTP server an API reference link to the overview here covers a lot of what
we're actually going to be doing in the course and the functions used.
And if you follow the second link, it just takes you to an example.
Further down on the same page, you'll find that our implementation follows a very similar structure
to this example shown here.
So let's take a look at some of the steps we'll have to take to get the web server up and running.
One of the first steps will take is embedding binary data the HTML, CSS and JavaScript files, so follow
the link for detail.
Basically, we're going to edit the see, make list file and list our web page files there.
Then, in the CTP server see file, we're going to add the files contents to the read only section in
the flesh, as shown here will then include our basic HTP server, start and stop functions and wrap
those functions so that we can use them in the application.
Similar to how it's done in the example here.
Next will then create the default 8TB server configuration, where some of these structure members will
be initialized using the default config function, but will adjust some of these members to our needs,
then we'll call the 8TB start function.
Things will turn out looking similar to the examples shown and throughout the course will create your
AI handlers.
And this is a you are a handler structure here.
And in the first lesson, we'll just register your AI handlers for the resource files and we'll create
this in a very similar way, as shown here.
And the last thing that I want to mention is that will also create a task called HGTV Server Monitor,
which can send and receive cue messages to respond to certain events.
It's similar to what we have in the Wi-Fi application for now will handle into test communication between
the Wi-Fi application and the web server in this manner by using the message cues.
If any of this seems confusing, don't worry.
Once we get to coding, it should start to make more sense.
I just like providing a quick overview so that you have some sort of reference before we get into using
the HGTV server API.
All right, so let's get to coding in the next section.